Preliminary Guide to the Rotary Club of Durham Records, 1915-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Rotary Club of Durham records 1915-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Rotary Club (Durham, N.C.)
19.5 Linear Feet 10,093 Items
The Rotary Club of Durham was chartered in 1915 as part of Rotary International, an organization of service clubs.
The records from the Rotary Club of Durham include bulletins, committee files, membership cards, board minutes, anniversary projects, photographs, scrapbooks, and other miscellaneous materials relating to the activities and members of the club.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Rotary Club of Durham Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Historical Note
The Rotary Club of Durham was first organized by Walter Holladay in November 1915 as a branch of Rotary International. In its early years, the club participated in numerous projects, including the building of Rotary Park in Durham, fundraising for community organizations, serving underprivileged children, and assisting the war effort through selling war bonds and volunteering for the Red Cross. Following World War II, the club began establishing loan funds and scholarship programs for students. It partnered with the Y.M.C.A. and sponsored camp programs for local youths. The Club also arranged exchanges with other Rotary Clubs internationally. The first woman was inducted into membership in 1988, and the Club celebrated its 90th Anniversary in 2005. The Club continues to operate in Durham.
Collection Overview
The records from the Rotary Club of Durham include bulletins, committee files, membership cards, board minutes, anniversary projects, photographs, scrapbooks, and other miscellaneous materials relating to the activities and members of the club.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Rotary Club (Durham, N.C.)
Volunteers
Durham (N.C.)
Rosters
Administrative records
Black-and-white photographs
Clippings
Newsletters
Contents of Collection
- Rotary Club of Durham Records, 1915-2005, 14 Boxes
  - Official Club bulletins, 1930-1996 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1915-1964 (Box 2)
  - Photographs and slides
  - Correspondence, 1964-1986 (Box 3)
  - Board minutes, 1915-1931
  - Board minutes, 1931-1949 (Box 4)
  - Membership cards (alphabetical)
  - Board minutes, 1949-1992 (Box 5)
  - Board minutes, 1992-1995 (Box 6)
  - Committee files
  - Miscellaneous files
  - Membership cards (alphabetical) (Box 7)
  - Club history and chronology
  - Rotary Archives files (re: Constitution, Rotary Club Fellowship candidates, activities) (Box 8)
  - Rotary Archives files, continued (Box 9)
  - Club directories, 1966-1997
  - 50th and 75th Anniversary files
  - Board minutes, 1995-1999 (Box 10)
  - School project files, 2000-2002
  - Membership resignations/terminations books (Box 11)
  - Club directories, 1931-1968
  - Park project file
  - Board minutes, 1996-1997 and 1999-2000
  - Board minutes, 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Rotary Headlines scrapbook, 1938-1949 (Box 13)
  - Rotary Headlines scrapbook, 1949-1951
  - Photo album, date unknown
  - Scrapbook, 1965
  - Scrapbook, 1983-1984 (Box 14)